[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
At the core of boosting is the idea of an ensemble classifier.
في جوهر التقوية يكمن المصنف المجمع.
So let's revisit the idea of, say, decision stump.
دعونا نعود إلى مفهوم فرع القرارات مثلًا.
A decision stump may take our data as input and might look at some particular
قد تأخذ فروع القرارات بياناتنا كمدخلات ثم تنظر إلى بعض الميزات المعينة
feature, let's say, income and ask, is income greater than 100K?
دعنا نقول، الدخل ثم تسأل، هل الدخل أكبر من 100 ألف؟
If yes, we say a loan is safe, and if not, we might say the loan is risky.
إذا كانت الإجابة بنعم، فنقترض أن القرض آمن، و إذا لم يكن كذلك، فنفترض أن القرض محفوف بالمخاطر.
And so the output here, y hat, is +1 or
وبذلك يكون الناتج هنا، y hat، هو 1+
-1, depending on whether we think the loan is safe or risky.
أو -1، اعتمادًا على ما إذا كنا نعتقد أن القرض آمن أم خطير.
We're going to use the following notation just to be clear in today's module.
سنستخدم الترميز التالي لمجرد التوضيح في وحدة اليوم.
We're going to use f(x) to denote one of these weak simple classifiers or
سنستخدم f (x) للدلالة على واحدة من تلك المصنفات البسيطة الضعيفة
a classifier in general, so that's the f.
أو المصنفات بشكل عام، هذا ما تمثله f.
And so what boosting does starts not just from a single decision stump,
فالتقوية لا تبدأ فقط من فرع قرار واحد،
but it combines many of them together in order to improve the prediction.
بل تجمع بين العديد من هذه العناصر معًا لتحسين التوقعات.
So, for example, you may have a decision stump that splits on income,
إذن، على سبيل المثال، قد يكون لديك فرع قرار ينقسم على الدخل،
another one that splits on credit history, another one on how much savings you have,
وآخر ينقسم على التاريخ الائتماني، وآخر على مقدار التوفير الذي لديك،
and the market conditions, and so on.
وحالات السوق، وما إلى ذلك.
So if you're giving a particular input, for example, your income is 120K,
فإذا أدخلت مدخلًا معينًا، على سبيل المثال، 120 ألفًا في حالة الدخل،
so the first decision boost here is going to vote with f1,
فإن أول تقوية للقرار هنا ستكون في صالح f1،
that the loan is safe, so it's going to vote +1.
مما يعني أن القرض آمن، لذلك سوف تصبح النتيجة +1.
But your credit history is bad, so
لكن تاريخك الائتماني سيئ
the second decision stump here is going to vote -1, f2.
وبالتالي فإن فرع القرار الثاني هنا سوف تصبح نتيجته -1، F2.
And, say, the third one, because your savings are low,
ولنفترض أن الثالث، لأن مدخراتك منخفضة،
is going to vote risky -1, and the third one,
ستكون عواقبه وخيمة لتصبح نتيجته -1، وحالة السوق،
market conditions, turned out to be good so you're going to vote +1.
للثالث، تبين أنها جيدة، وبالتالي تصبح النتيجة +1.
And the question here the boosting asks is, how do you combine in an ensemble
والسؤال الذي تطرحه التقويات هو، كيف يمكنك الجمع
way this -1, +1 votes from different classifiers, f1 through f4, in this case.
بين نتائج -1 و +1 من المصنفات المختلفة، في تلك الحالة من f1 إلى f4.
And so the way that we combine is by having some sort of weights that deal with
فالطريقة التي نجمع بها هي من خلال وجود نوع من الأوزان يتعامل مع
what is called the ensemble models.
ما يسمى نماذج المجموعة.
So the weights here are w1, w2, w3, w4.
تتمثل الأوزان هنا في w1 و w2 و w3 و w4.
And we multiply the outputs from each of the classifiers, add them up together and
نقوم بضرب النواتج من كل من المصنفات، وإضافتها معاً
then take the sign of that.
ثم نأخذ العلامة من ذلك.
If the sign is positive, we output +1.
إذا كانت العلامة موجبة، فيكون الناتج 1+.
If the sign is negative, we output -1.
إذا كانت العلامة سالبة، فيكون الناتج -1.
So it's kind of a weighted voting schema.
وهو يعتبر نوعًا ما طريقة ترجيحية موزونة.
This weighted voting schema, amazing, really awesome.
الطريقة الترجيحية الموزونة، مذهلة، رائعة حقًا.
And let's see a little bit more of what that looks like.
دعونا نتعرف عليها أكثر.
So let's suppose that we have a particular set of weights and
لنفترض أن لدينا مجموعة محددة من الأوزان
we have multiple decision stumps, so classifiers that have provided their vote.
ولدينا فروعًا متعددة للقرارات، أو بمعنى آخر نتائج المصنفات.
Let's see more explicitly what that output value would be.
دعونا نرى بشكل أكثر وضوحًا ماذا ستكون قيمة المخرجات المذكورة.
So, for example, if the weights of each classifier is shown on the right here,
إذن، على سبيل المثال، إذا تم عرض أوزان كل مصنف على اليمين هنا،
then we're going to say that output that we're going to predict is going to be
سنقول إن الناتج الذي سوف نتوقعه سيكون علامة
the sign of w1, which is 2.
w1 وهو 2.
Then multiply the vote of f1, which is +1 plus w2, which is 1.5, so
ثم اضرب نتيجة f1، وهي +1 زائد w2، وهي 1.5،
we believe that the second decision stump is not as important as the first one,
ولهذا، نعتقد أن فرع القرار الثاني ليس مهمًا مثل الأول،
and the vote there was -1, so that multiplies -1.
وكان الترجيح هنا -1، بحيث تتضاعف -1.
Then, for the third one, again, we say that the weight is 1.5, and
ثم، بالنسبة للثالث، مرة أخرى، نفترض أن الوزن هو 1.5،
again we say it's not as important as the first one, but
مرة أخرى نقول إنه ليس مهمًا مثل الأول،
as important as the second one, and the prediction there was -1.
لكن لا يقل أهمية عن الثاني، والتنبؤ كان -1.
And finally, for the last one, we might say that the weight is 0.5.
وأخيرًا، بالنسبة إلى الأخير، قد نفترض أن الوزن هو 0.5.
So this is the least important of all of these classifiers.
وهو الأقل أهمية من بين كل هذه المصنّفات.
And the function here that, the output of f4 here was +1, was a safe loan.
والدالة هنا، حيث ناتج F4 هو +1، مما يعني قرضًا آمنًا.
So we have these votes, these weights, we multiply them together and
إذاً لدينا هذه الترجيحات، وهذه الأوزان، نقوم بضربهم سويًا
we see that the output of this F classifier for
لنرى أن الناتج لهذا المصنف F
the input xi is the sign of -0.5, which is equal to or
أو المدخل xi هو علامة -0.5، التي تساوي
implies that y hat i is -1.
أو تعني بأن y hat i هي -1.
So even though there was two positive votes and two negative votes, and the most
على الرغم من وجود اثنين من الترجيحات الإيجابية واثنين من الترجيحات السلبية،
important classifier, the first one, was a positive vote, when you add it up and
وأهم المصنفات، الذي يتمثل في المصنف الأول، كان إيجابيًا بالترجيح، فعند إضافته
you average the results, you get a risky loan as an output.
وأخذ متوسط النتائج، تحصل على قرض محفوف بالمخاطر كمخرج.
Now this is a simple example of what's called an ensemble classifier or
الآن هذا مثال بسيط لما يسمى بالمصنف المجمع
the combination multiple classifiers.
أو مصنفات الجمع المتعددة.
As we'll see, this kind of ensemble model,
كما سنرى، هذا النوع من نموذج المجموعة،
this kind of combination is what everybody uses in industry to be able to
هذا النوع من الدمج هو ما يستخدمه الجميع في هذا المجال حتى يتمكنوا من
solve complex decision problems, complex classification problems.
حل مشاكل القرار المعقدة، أو بمعنى آخر مشاكل التصنيف المعقدة.
Just to make sure we're all on the same page,
فقط للتأكد من أننا جميعًا متفقون،
I'm going to just formally define the ensemble learning problem.
سأقوم فقط بتحديد مسألة لتعلم المجموعة.
So we're given some data, where y is either +1 or -1,
لدينا بعض البيانات، حيث y إما 1+ أو -1،
there's also multiclass version of this, we're just going to talk about +1 or
هناك أيضًا نسخة متعددة الفئات من هذا، لكننا سنتحدث فقط عن 1+ أو -1
-1 in today's module, and we have some input, x.
في وحدة اليوم، ولدينا بعض المدخلات، x.
We have some data that allows us to learn f1, f2, all the way to fT,
ولدينا بعض البيانات التي تسمح لنا بمعرفة f1 و f2، حتى fT،
which are the T weight classifiers, or just classifiers, that we learn from data.
وهي المصنفات الضعيفة T، أو فقط المصنفات، التي نتعلمها من البيانات.
And then some coefficients that we learn from data, w-hat1,
ثم بعض المعاملات التي نتعلمها من البيانات، w-hat1،
w-hat2, all the way to w-hatT.
و w-hat2 حتى w-hatT.
And once we learn them, making a prediction is very similar
وبمجرد التعلم، يصبح التنبؤ مشابهًا جدًا
to what you do for logistic regression or a linear classifier.
لما نفعله مع الانحدار اللوجستي أو المصنف الخطي.
It's just the sign of the weighted sum of the votes from each classifier.
هو مجرد علامة مجموع الترجيحات الموزونة لكل مصنف.
And so if you look at this, it looks a lot like a linear classification model,
لذا إذا نظرت إلى ذلك، ستلاحظ أنه يشبه إلى حد كبير نموذج التصنيف الخطي،
logistic regression and all of those, exactly the same.
والانحدار اللوجستي وهكذا، بالضبط نفس الشيء.
However, not only are we learning the ws from data,
ومع ذلك، فنحن لا نتعرف فقط على قيم w من البيانات،
we're actually learning the features.
بل نحن في الواقع نتعرف على الميزات.
In those models, we had hs to represent our features.
وفي هذه النماذج، كان لدينا h لتمثيل الميزات.
Here, the feature are these fs,
لكن هنا تتمثل الميزات في f،
which are the weight classifiers that we're going to learn from data.
وهي التصنيفات الضعيفة، التي سنتعلمها من البيانات.
So we can think about boosting as an approach to learn features from data.
لذلك يمكننا التفكير في التقوية كطريقة لتعلم الميزات من البيانات.
And it's really super exciting.
وهي حقًا شيقة جدًا.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]